♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
- ♪ Fix it ♪
- ♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
[staff] The girl who was with you, Ibyang.
She's in the lobby drinking water.
She said she got lost
in the forest earlier.
- [Atoy] What about Janine?
- [Gemma] Oh, no! Why did they go there?
There are monitor lizards
and snakes there.
Especially now, it's summer.
- [Atoy] She was bitten by a snake.
- [Audrey, in English] Oh, no!
[Karla] Where did you get this?
You never got those before.
Is it Dad?
This wouldn't have happened
to our daughter if Ibyang wasn't here!
I know Ibyang.
She's not a bad child.
She wouldn't do that.
She deliberately made me get lost.
Was that really her intention?
Don't you believe me?
- [woman] There are no women's clothes.
- [Karla] Ten pesos, one garment!
This is mine! These are my clothes, huh!
Everything I earn here,
I'll give to you so you can leave!
[sobs]
[Cita] I'll kill you first
before you kill my child.
We're done.
Leave!
[Noel] You should be thankful
I accepted your child,
even if she's not mine!
[Noel] Delfin!
Delfin is your father!
Atoy is your brother!
[Audrey] Your child is looking for you!
She's not even your child!
[Ibyang] It's true.
[Audrey] But you can only have one child.
Janine or Ibyang.
You fought with Aunt Audrey because of me.
Well, I believe you.
[Atoy] I know
you didn't do anything wrong.
PREVIOUSLY
Come on. I'll take you home.
[music fades]
Sir Noel.
You're really something else, huh?
You know, ever since
you lost your job,
you've done nothing but cause trouble
here in our barangay, huh?
How can I help you?
[scoffs]
I don't need your help.
Then who will help you?
Miss Cita?
[pensive music playing]
She already kicked you out, right?
We'll reconcile!
We've been like this for a long time.
We fight, then make up.
But in the end, I'm still her husband.
She can't do anything.
There's no divorce
here in the Philippines,
so she has no choice!
It's still me.
[sarcastic laugh] Okay.
So, you think…
You think Miss Cita won't leave you?
You almost stabbed her child
in front of her.
Right?
You should be taken
straight to the precinct. Huh?
There's no divorce there,
but there is jail.
[chuckles sarcastically]
Hey, Paldo!
You act as if you have done no wrong.
Weren't you once the troublemaker
here in the barangay!
You even stole the statue of San Antonio--
What?
[dramatic stinging]
That wasn't proven.
If I was a troublemaker then…
I've changed.
That's called character development.
Which you don't have,
because you never changed.
[Noel] Oh, see. She even came here.
She's here to pick me up.
She'll coax me to come home--
You got some nerve!
You think I'm here to pick you up
to come home?!
Here are your things!
Don't ever show yourself
to me and Karla again, huh!
I'll press charges against you
for what you did to my child!
Rot in jail!
- Rot in jail!
- Cita. Cita!
The nerve of you!
Cita!
[tense music playing]
[Noel gasps]
[music fades]
[suave theme music playing]
[crickets chirping]
[Atoy] Oh, you should rest, Janine.
So we can do activities tomorrow.
Uh, Daddy.
Can you sleep in my and Mommy's room,
so we'll be complete, the three of us?
Uh, I'll let Ibyang know. All right.
Go on, go inside.
My dear, you go ahead.
Have you talked to Ibyang?
[somber music playing]
Not yet.
When do you plan to talk to her?
[melancholic music playing]
You know, Atoy…
Let's not waste time.
If you can't let go of Ibyang,
I won't force you.
But we can't be together
if you can't choose our daughter.
Audrey.
Maybe we made a mistake
trying to build this family.
Stay here with Ibyang.
My child and I will go home.
Audrey, no. Don't.
[music fades]
Don't leave.
Okay? I love you and Janine.
[somber music playing]
I want us to be whole.
[sentimental music playing]
Karla is really unlucky
to have him as her dad.
I mean, she's not even adopted,
and he has such
a bad attitude towards her.
You know, you're the opposite.
Because you, even if
you're not his real child,
Atoy loves you so much.
Yes, that's true.
[Ame] Oh?
Why does your voice sound sad?
Janine is the culprit again, isn't she?
What's the problem?
I thought things
were okay with Aunt Audrey.
But she made Tatoy choose
between me or Janine.
Choose one, she said.
Really?
So, what did Atoy say?
I didn't hear, actually.
[melancholic music playing]
Ibyang, don't be sad, okay?
I'm sure Atoy won't leave you.
[Ame] He'll make a compromise.
And he won't just abandon you.
See, you're still there up to now.
You're still together.
That's true.
All right then, Ibyang.
Go to sleep. It's late. Good night!
Good night.
[melodramatic music playing]
[crickets chirping]
[phone vibrating]
Atoy.
What? Did Miss Cita call you?
She had a fight with Sir Noel.
We brought him to the barangay.
Anyway, I'll tell you the story later.
So, how was your vacation with the kids?
[pensive music playing]
Huh?
Why are you asking me to fetch her?
What's the problem
between Janine and Ibyang?
[heavy music playing]
'Son, thank you.
Have you told Ibyang yet?
[Atoy] Not yet.
Wait--
[Ibyang] Oh?
Brother Emerson!
You're here too?
Are you joining us for fishing?
Uh, Ibyang. Come here for a moment.
Um, I just need
to tell you something, okay?
[clears throat]
Your Brother Emerson is here…
to take you home, to accompany you.
[somber music playing]
I'm sorry, Ibyang.
[melancholic music playing]
This is hard for me too, but…
this is so you and Janine
won't fight anymore, okay?
But I thought you believed me?
Yes, I believe you.
And I'm proud of you
because you still do the right thing,
even when no one is watching.
That's what I always tell you.
[dramatic flourish]
[melodramatic music playing]
But why are you sending me home?
I didn't do anything wrong.
Why are you punishing me?
No, no.
I'm not punishing you.
I'm not. I'm not punishing you.
I'm just saying…
I'm only doing this for Janine, okay?
I hope you understand, Ibyang.
So, you chose Janine?
You won't adopt me anymore?
[dramatic music playing]
Lord…
Lord, am I a bad person if…
I chose my own child over Ibyang?
[music fades]
[in English] I'm sorry.
Mommy?
You're crying?
Why?
Your daddy is sending Ibyang home.
[heavy music playing]
I'm crying because…
I just feel sorry for her.
But this is the only way I know…
so there won't be any more conflict.
Mommy, don't cry anymore,
because you and Daddy are back together,
and we're complete now.
We want you to feel that Daddy
and I love you very much, child.
[sighs, then sobs]
[music fades]
[intense music playing]
[sobbing]
[wailing]
[melancholic music playing]
This isn't easy for me either, Ibyang.
[sobbing]
That's enough.
I'm sorry.
[sobbing]
I'll never have a real family.
No. You'll still have a real family.
Huh? I'm still here.
You have Miss Cita.
And you have Sister Karla.
You can still come
to the house anytime you want.
[Atoy] But of course,
it's different
when you have a real family,
when you're the top priority.
A father and mother
who think of no one else but you,
and that’s what I’ll look for, for you.
[sobs]
But you're the father I want.
You're the best!
[sobbing]
I'm sure there's someone else
out there who's even better.
But he won't be Tatoy.
[sobbing]
Come on. Ibyang, let's go.
- No, I don't want to!
- Come on.
- [melodramatic music playing]
- [indistinct]
[Ibyang] I don't want to.
Come on. All right. You should go now.
Do you want a treat?
What do you want, huh?
When I come back.
Do you want siomai?
Pares? Do you want pares?
Come on.
[Emerson] Come on, come on.
Go, go on.
Come on, come on.
I just wish…
I was your real child.
So you wouldn't give me away.
You're my only Tatoy.
And you're my only Ibyang.
- [dramatic music playing]
- [Atoy] Go on.
[sobbing]
[Ame] Why is Atoy like that?
Choosing that troublesome Janine?
[Emerson] Ame, that's his child.
Of course, he'll choose her.
But he should have fought for Ibyang.
[melancholic music playing]
Believe me, it's hard for him too.
He couldn't even say it.
Don't make him out to be the villain.
[Ame] He gave the child false hope.
He promised her.
That's really painful for Ibyang.
Look at her!
She's never cried like this before!
[Emerson clicks tongue] Yes.
I can feel her pain.
So, imagine how Atoy must feel.
But Atoy has a family.
He shouldn't have promised to adopt Ibyang
if he wasn't going to do it.
[sobbing]
[Ame] Ibyang…
I'm here, okay?
Sister Ame…
I'm used to it being just the two of us.
[melodramatic music playing]
[sobbing] If Tatoy doesn't want me,
then fine.
I won't force myself…
on someone who can't choose me.
That's enough.
Sis Ame is here, okay?
[hushing]
Come here.
- [wailing]
- [dramatic music playing]
I'm here.
FATHER'S LANE
FOOD HUB IN BACLARAN
[woman] Sis, let's go. Come on!
I don't want to. I don't have--
I don't have money.
- Miss Cita, are you okay?
- Yes.
Psst. Hey, Cita.
Did Noel get out of jail?
What? Did he fight with you again?
Huh?
No.
I'm looking for my daughter.
- Have you seen Karla?
- Karla?
- Seems like--
- No, no.
Well, maybe your daughter
is still sleeping.
It's still early.
- I checked her room. She wasn't there.
- [woman] Hmm?
She wasn't at the basketball court either.
Where could she have gone?
- Oh, I saw her!
- [woman] Oh, oh!
Where?
She rode a jeepney.
Looked like it was bound for San Roque.
- A jeepney?
- Yes, she got on a jeep.
[both] What?
[suspicious music playing]
[music fades]
[birds chirping]
Dad…
It must feel good
to say that face-to-face, right?
For the longest time,
I really thought of you as my father.
[sentimental music playing]
But now that I learned it's true,
I don't know how I should feel.
I'm happy,
but…
it's embarrassing.
I'm the result of your betrayal of Mom.
I don't even know if you knew
I was your child.
Delfin knew you were his youngest.
[melodramatic music playing]
[wind chimes clinking]
[music fades]
Ibyang!
Miss Cita?
[sighs]
Ibyang?
'Nang?
[knocks on door]
- 'Toy.
- Oh?
- Mmm, bro.
What's this? Is this your gift for us?
Psst, hey.
Don't touch that. It's Ibyang's.
[Atoy] Where are they?
I don't know.
Hmm, I just left them here last night.
[mysterious music playing]
ATOY, IBYANG AND I LEFT
THE CHILD WANTED TO DO SO
DON'T COME AND FIND US
They left?
Why didn't you tell me?
I didn't know, 'Toy.
Last night, I just left them here.
They were sad.
I didn't hear anything about leaving.
Where could they have gone?
[music fades]
Forgive me.
I didn't tell you the truth.
I planned to take
this secret to the grave,
just like Delfin did.
Why didn't Dad tell me?
[melancholic music playing]
We agreed not to tell you.
He forgave me, but…
he didn't forgive Delfin.
That's why he poured all his anger on you.
That's why I never felt that Dad loved me.
That's why he was always angry with me.
[melodramatic music playing]
Because I'm the outcome of your sin.
Forgive me.
[sobs] I didn't defend you
against Noel before.
I absorbed and accepted
all his hurtful words.
Because it was my fault,
so I had to accept it.
But what about Brother Atoy?
Did he just accept everything too?
[music fades]
He doesn't know.
What?!
[heavy music playing]
So, he looks like an idiot too,
because he doesn't know the truth?
Mom, we should tell him.
Do you think I don't want to tell him?
[sobs] Do you think I don't
want to ask his forgiveness?
I regret all my sins, Karla.
Believe me.
But Delfin made me promise
not to tell Atoy,
because he didn't want his son
to have no one to trust.
So, what now?
You want me to join you in fooling us?
Pretend everything's fine?
That everything's back to normal?
[Cita] My child…
[sobs]
Sorry, Mom, but I can't do that.
Brother Atoy is so kind to us.
He deserves to know the truth.
That's the problem!
Do you want to repay
his kindness with pain?
Karla, I'm begging you.
If he finds out the truth,
surely, he won't forgive me.
Promise me, Karla.
[sobs] You won't tell him.
[somber music playing]
[sobbing]
[epic music playing]
[birds chirping]
Full!
Thank you, Miss Cita.
Um, I still have a little money.
We'll contribute here.
No, don't think about that.
This house is open for you,
and it's even better
that you're staying here with me.
And Sis Karla?
Is she okay?
Because last night she seemed sad.
She didn't talk to me.
Does she have a problem?
[Ame] What problem would Karla have?
She should be happy now,
since Sir Noel is gone.
- [Atoy] 'Nang?
- [Ame] Hey.
- [Atoy] 'Nang!
- It's Atoy.
- [knocks on door]
- [Atoy] Godmother Cita!
- It's A--Iit's Atoy.
[suspicious music playing]
[Cita] Um…
[Atoy] 'Nang!
How are you?
Well, Ibyang left me.
She's upset with me.
She's sulking.
[sneaky music playing]
Godmother…
Are they here?
[tense music playing]
Wow, you look different.
You're sharper than a needle.
Oh my God!
Is it true, Atoy?
That… you're like a secret killer spy?
[Red] You need to talk to Audrey.
Tell her it's a bad idea
to get back together with Atoy.
What's wrong with that?
I hit-and-run Atoy's father.
Our family will be destroyed
if those two end up together.
UP NEXT
You're not just a tracker,
you're also a marksman.
Just inspired, sir.
And this is what I'll do
to the one who ran over my father.
♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
♪ Fix it ♪
Subtitle translation by: Rachel C. Arias